[bright music]
[phone rings]
You know I'm working, right?
Sorry, this will be quick.
I just need to buy some
chicken, veggies, groceries.
Do you know where the nearest
and cheapest grocery store is?
Emphasis on the word cheapest.
Google Maps?
Oh, okay.
Google Map –
Come on, I know where
the nearest grocery store is.
What I don’t know is which
one is the most affordable.
You know my budget is kind of limited.
Super Mart?
Super Mart. Okay, thanks.
- Is that all? - Yeap.
Well, actually don’t eat dinner tonight.
I’m cooking.
What makes you so sure
I'll eat what you'll cook?
I just wanted to thank you for cooking
the best meal I had since I got to LA.
Okay, it wasn’t…
You were very hungry
and you hadn’t had
anything better in a while.
Well, you still didn’t have
to go through all the trouble.
It’s only because you got hurt because
I got you that gig at the liquor store.
[playful music]
So you only did that out of guilt?
That’s the only reason you were nice to me?
I thought this was gonna be a short call?
Okay. Well, I’m...
Hello?
Well, nice talking to you too.
Bye, Josh.
[playful music]
Shit, that’s my bus.
45 minutes?
Why is there no tricycle here?
It’s good for the heart.
Why is it so hot here?
I thought it’s always cold in the US.
Hey, sir.
Sir!
Hey.
Do I… Do I look familiar?
- What the fuck? - Do I look familiar?
Get out of my way.
[street noise]
God, I’m starving.
Where is he?
[bright music]
Surprise!
What the?
What are you doing?
Heard you were looking for me.
Miss me much?
I don’t miss you.
I’m starving and you said
you’d take care of dinner.
But I guess you didn’t so
I’ll heat up some leftovers.
Who said I didn’t take care of dinner?
What’s that?
Jollibee.
What’s Jollibee?
Oh, don’t tell me you
haven’t heard of Jollibee?
No.
This is the most popular fast
food chain in the Philippines.
Okay. So are we ginna eat together?
Or are you just gonna keep
endorsing your national fast food chain?
Did you just ask if we’re
gonna eat together?
I didn’t mean it like that.
But it doesn’t matter anyways
because I only got one meal.
And it’s for you.
Oh, aren’t you gonna eat?
You said you were starving earlier.
I don’t wanna eat.
Why?
Because you’ve got nothing to eat.
Oh, so you’re concerned about me?
Shut up.
Don’t worry about me. I eat
Jollibee all the time in Manila.
This one’s for you.
Come on. Go ahead and eat it.
Fine.
I think you’re gonna like it.
And you probably won’t admit it.
Because that’s kind of what you do.
Where are you going?
[bright music]
There.
- But... - Hep, hep, hep...
just eat.
So...
does that mean that this
is officially our first date?
What are you talking about?
This. Us. Eating together.
No, this is not a date.
This is me not wanting to eat
alone and have you look at me.
Mmm...
But I always look at you.
Will you stop being so…
So…
sweet? Charming? Lovable?
Charming?
Lovable?
I was gonna say insufferable.
What happened to your plan, by the way?
What plan?
Your plan to go out and buy
some rice and veggies and chicken,
and cook some Filipino food?
Oh, yeah. No, um…
Nothing happened. I just
thought this would be better.
You know, you can’t cover everything
up with this everything’s okay attitude.
You can tell me.
What happened?
Nothing happened.
Um, I just...
um,
thought this would be better.
I hate you for being a liar.
I'm not a liar.
Really?
Give me an update about
your Hollywood project then.
Oh, um, that…
Yeah, no, um,
it’s going, uh, great!
We already started treatment on the script.
Wow.
What’s it about?
What’s it about? Um,
Yeah, no, it's um,
The story is about…
It’s about
um, something I can’t talk about.
Because we have
confidentiality agreements, NDAs.
Got it.
[bright music]
By the way, there’s a job opening
at the liquor store, if you want it.
One of the other crew members resigned.
Oh, why?
I don’t know.
Could it have anything to
do with unfair labor practices?
I don’t know where this is
going. Do you want the job or not?
- No, yeah, yeah.
- Okay, because you seem more interested
in why this other crew member resigned.
I’m a writer.
I’m always more
interested in the backstory.
Okay.
Well, if you want, you can start tomorrow,
5pm – 10pm.
70 bucks.
70 bucks for 5 hours.
3,500 pesos?
I don’t know US dollars to pesos.
I wanna hug you right now.
Please don’t.
I think deep down inside,
some part of you likes me.
No, not even a little.
Right. So who’s lying now?
I had an opening for a job.
You’ve said you needed a job.
I offered you the job.
And you accepted the job.
I don’t know what about
that implies that I like you.
Maybe the part where you just
can’t help but do a few things for me.
You know, sometimes
it’s not what people say.
Sometimes it’s what they do.
[bright music]
What?
No comeback?
You’re a writer.
I don’t argue with writers.
You have a response plotted out in
your head. I can’t compete with that.
I’m just gonna enjoy this moment.
Eating Jollibee for the first time, I mean.
And you’re right.
It’s very good.
[bright music]
Really, bestfriend?
He pushed you?
That's sad.
I know, right?
I mean, he could've just easily ran away.
But to push your son who
you saw for the first time?
But are you sure that he's your dad?
What if he just looks like him?
It already happened before, remember?
You have mistaken someone else as your dad.
And now, you're in America.
A lot more people look like your dad.
I don't know, bestfriend.
But wait bestfriend...
why are you like that?
What do you mean?
You just saw someone who
you thought was your father.
Then he pushed you to the
ground and told you to go away.
So?
Shouldn’t you be sad and miserable?
You've been looking for him since birth.
But why do you seem so happy?
You're blooming!
I just don't want to
waste my time and energy
thinking about people who don't want me.
He left me and my mom,
abandoned us as if we meant nothing.
If he doesn’t want to accept me,
that's fine.
It’s his loss, not mine.
It doesn’t feel that way, bestfriend.
Tell me what you think then.
You’re in love!
I knew it!
My instincts never fail me!
You've already found someone new!
Just less than a month in America
and you're already flirting!
Bestfriend,
You know you're my one and only.
Even if I met the most important,
amazing person in the world,
no one could ever replace you in my heart.
That's so romantic!
Happy now?
[bright music]
Oh, what happened?
Turn it off.
I'm sleeping.
Oh.
Sorry.
Hey, what time am I supposed
to report to work tomorrow?
Hey, um, what part of I'm
sleeping don't you understand?
Sorry, Josh.
And what part of "don't call
me Josh" don't you understand?
What's wrong? We were
just having a good time earlier.
- We’re being really sweet
and – - I wasn’t being sweet.
But you were.
How many times do I have to tell you?
I was looking for a replacement
crew member at work.
And it just so happened that
you were also looking for a job.
Okay? That’s it.
Stop making a big deal of it.
Says the guy who was just
splitting his meal into half for me
and seemed kind of sweet to me.
I didn’t want to eat your food
and you need more money than I do.
You couldn’t even
afford two Jollibee meals.
So that’s it?
Just like that.
We're back to the beginning
and it’s just all about money?
It’s always just been about the money.
You’re not part of my life.
Give me 300 or you’re out in three days.
Hey, what are you doing?
Hey!
Where are you going?
[street noise]
[soft music]
Answer the phone please...
Hey, where the hell are you?
I’m fine. Don’t worry about me.
It’s three in the morning
and it’s not safe out there.
I can take care of myself.
Look, we both have to go to sleep.
Just come back. We’ll talk
about this in the morning.
Don’t worry.
I’ll get you the rest of your rent money.
Okay look, I’m sorry for everything I said.
I am sorry that I hurt you.
Please just come back.
I’m really sorry. I’m really
fucking worried about you.
I’ll come pick you up. Where are you?
[soft music]
Thanks.
Are you okay?
You know, even if you're mad,
you shouldn't go out there
in the middle of the night.
- It's not safe— - I saw him.
Who?
I saw my father.
Or someone who looks like him. I don't...
I don't know.
I was walking back from the groceries
when I just spotted him.
My mom met my dad when he
was stationed in the Philippines.
He was in the U.S. Navy,
I think.
But he left us right after I was born.
My mom says there was a
volcanic eruption in our province.
And all the US troops had to be pulled out.
That's why I never met him.
So I always grew up wondering
what it was like to have a father,
just like any other kid.
My mom said never to look for him,
not to bother.
[soft music]
But you know me,
I'm stubborn.
So a couple of years ago,
I asked a friend of mine
who lived here in the US
to help me with my father.
And I don't know how he did it, but
he found out a lot about him.
His email, pictures,
his home address, Facebook accounts.
It’s kind of funny because
he had like ten of them.
I was so excited back then
because I thought this is it.
I’m finally gonna meet my father.
So like the next day, I emailed him.
I messaged all his Facebook accounts.
But you know what he did?
He deactivated all his Facebook accounts,
the email I sent bounced.
He couldn’t bother to say
“Hey, um, it’s me.
It’s nice to meet you son.
I’m sorry things turned out
the way they did. But, uh,
you know, I got a wife and kids
and I don’t want you to ruin that.”
[dramatic music]
Because at least that would
have been an acknowledgment.
At least that would have been an
acknowledgment that I’m his son.
That’s all I wanted from him.
Because I don’t need anything from him.
I don’t need money from him.
My mom’s worked hard her entire life
so she could give us everything we needed.
I’m just…
I’m just starting to sound
crazy and desperate.
You know, because deep down inside I know…
He doesn’t want me.
He doesn’t care about me.
And I’m never gonna see him.
[dramatic music]
- Good morning. - Good morning.
Did you want me to help you with that?
No, I’m good. You can
make some coffee if you want.
Okay. Did you want me to make you some?
No, I’m good. I don’t drink coffee.
You are the first person I’ve
ever met who doesn’t drink coffee.
[bright music]
This is really good.
Thank you!
You know, you should start a food business.
Yeah, like Korean food. Samgyupsal.
You won’t even start with
something big like a restaurant.
You could just do like
online orders, food deliveries.
Oh, maybe even a food truck!
I don’t want to do that.
This is egg and bread.
Okay, but one day, you’re
gonna look back at this moment
and you’re gonna think I really
should have listened to that Andre.
As for me, I’m gonna miss your
cooking when I go back to the Philippines.
Isn’t there Korean food there?
Yeah, but you know,
it’s different without...
Actually, um, can I ask you something?
Yeah, sure.
Promise you’re not gonna get mad?
Depends on the question.
Um, never mind.
You can’t do that. You can’t start
asking question and then say never mind.
Then promise me you’re not gonna get mad.
Fine, I promise.
What happened with you last night?
What do you mean what
happened with me last night?
We’re having a nice night, sharing a meal.
And then I went to CR.
The CR?
Uh, yeah, that's what we call it,
CR. Stands for Comfort Room.
Oh, the bathroom.
Um, yeah.
So I went to the CR,
or uh, bathroom.
And when I got back, you were mad.
Yeah, um…
I told you to never make
phone calls in the bathroom.
What if I need to pee?
That’s it? That’s why you were mad?
Oh, okay.
You could have just knocked.
You know what,
I promise I will never again
take a phone call from in the toilet.
- In the toilet? - In the bathroom.
[bright music]
Hey, can I ask you something too?
Yeah, you can ask me anything.
I know it’s none of my business
but that’s your partner, right?
Huh?
Lover, significant other, special someone?
The person you were talking
to on the phone last night.
I’m not following.
You can tell me. It’s okay.
Well, I’m not in a relationship.
But if you’re asking who I
was talking to last night, uh...
Oh yeah, I was talking to my bestfriend.
A lot of people sometimes think we’re
together because we call each other “besh”
and we’re so ridiculous but...
Wait.
Is that why you got mad last night?
What? No!
You were jealous!
Stop it. I wasn’t.
- You were jealous!
- No, no! I told you I wasn’t jealous.
You don’t have to worry about “besh”.
You know what, I’m
gonna introduce you to her.
You don’t have to do that.
I want to.
I want her to know who’s
making me smile while I’m here.
Even if my luck has
otherwise run out in LA.
[bright music]